With every analytics project or analytics endeavor,
对于任何分析项目或者尝试
we must report on our data.
我们都需要做数据汇报
Now, we've touched on the importance of always having an action for our metrics.
之前我们讲了对于指标 要有可执行方案的重要性
But let's talk deeper on how we
现在 我们深入讲解该如何汇报
distribute and share the actions that we want to take place.
以及分享我们的行动建议
Within your marketing career,
在你的市场营销生涯里
you're going to be tasked with building reports.
作报告是不可避免的
Reports are how you share your findings,
报告是你来分享你的发现
and socialize the recommendations.
然后提出你的建议
Essentially, you'll use reports to inform others of what action you hope to see happen.
最重要的是 你要利用汇报来告诉其他人 你希望采取什么样的行动
You're going to be framing the problem,
你需要分析问题
and then proposing a solution or indicating that somebody needs to find that solution.
提出解决方案 或者建议相关人员去找到解决方案
So when it comes to building great reports,
作报告的时候
it's important that you keep things simple.
很重要的一点是保持简洁
Most of your analytics data would be presented as slides,
大多数分析报告可以以 PPT 的形式展示
and you should start by gathering the following information: your overview.
你可以报告以下内容：首先 概述
What's the goal or the objectives that you're measuring against?
目标或者你希望达到的成绩是什么？
This is essentially why you started this project.
你需要解释为什么希望做这个分析
So you want to frame what's going on.
你可以先分析问题
Next is your hypothesis.
然后做出假设
What did you expect to happen?
你希望发生什么？
What was the desired outcome?
你希望看到的结果是什么？
Was your hypothesis true or false?
你的假设是正确的还是错误的？
From there, it's important to explain the methodology.
这时候 解释你的方法也是很重要的
How much data was collected,
收集了多少数据
and where was that data collected?
从哪里收集到的数据
You're trying to help everyone understand that your findings are accurate.
因为你要让每个人都认可你的发现是准确的
From here, well, the actual data.
再然后就是 真实的数据
These are the metrics that you measured,
你的评估指标
and the graphs and charts that go with them.
以及相应的各类图表
Finally, your recommendations.
最后 你的建议
What should happen now that someone has seen this data?
现在大家都看到了这些数据 接下来该做什么呢
Typically, you keep this to three to five tactics.
通常你可以提议 3-5 个建议
Things that are immediately executable.
这些建议应该是可以立即执行的
They can include your social media tactics,
可以是社交媒体建议
or any other communications based on those findings.
或者基于这些发现的其他建议
Finally, at the end of your presentation,
最后 在 PPT 的结尾
you can include everything else.
可以包括其他所有相关信息
This is your backup research,
比如你的备用研究
any findings you've had,
你的发现
or all of the additional information that you
或者其他与讨论相关的
believe adds additional context to the conversation.
任何有用信息
It's there just in case the conversation warrants it.
以防一旦需要
Now, as you sit down to create your report,
接下来 我们写报告的时候
you want to think about who's reading it.
要考虑你的受众是谁
While we talked about the foundations,
刚才说的是一个报告基本会包括的内容
you'll ultimately customize this to
但最终你会根据你的受众来
the audience that you're presenting this information to.
定制一些信息
You may need to add more information, or remove it.
增加或者删除一些信息
Simply use that foundation as a starting point.
这些基本内容只是初稿
But let's talk about how we can adapt
现在 我们来讲如何根据受众
these reports depending on who typically receives them.
来定制这些报告
Now when it comes to sharing your data,
通常 你报告的对象会是这么几类人：管理高层
or somebody who's in a management position,
经理级别
or perhaps to an analyst for further review.
或者是分析师 他们会更深入地分析
Executives like everything short.
高层都喜欢简洁的东西
They're hoping to see a very small amount of data.
他们只希望看到最有用的数据
They don't have time for the whole picture.
他们没有时间去把所有的东西都看一遍
Management is really looking at how they take action.
经理级别的通常比较关注行动方案
They'd like to see a bigger picture,
他们会希望看到更多的信息
so they can understand whether or not the actions make sense.
以判断这个行动方案合不合理
The analyst, well, they want all of the data.
分析师则是希望看到所有的信息
They're hoping to help understand and reframe
他们希望看到问题是如何分析的 框架是怎样的
the problem in a way that arrives at action.
行动方案是怎么做出来的
Let's talk a little bit more about the executives.
关于高层人员 我们再说多一点
Here's some information that you can include.
你可以包括以下内容
First, your project scope.
第一 项目内容
You want to remind them what you are working on.
你要给他们一些背景信息
Not every executive is going to know about
不是每个高层管理人员都知道公司里
every objective that's going on in the company.
发生的每一个项目
So you want to frame the problem around that project scope.
所以你要围绕着项目 展开问题分析
Who started it, who was working on it,
谁起的头 项目团队都有谁
and what was the outcome,
结果是什么
or where were you headed?
你的预期是什么
Now, this is really going to be your overview and hypotheses slides mixed together,
这个部分既有概述 也有假设
including those details on that team leadership.
也包括了团队人员组成
Next, talk about the key data points.
第二 关键数据
Again, keep it simple.
还是建议以简洁为主
Most executives don't care about all of the data that you have.
大多数高层不会去关心你的所有的数据
Now, when it comes to your methodology,
第三 你采用的方法
this is typically less important.
这部分比较次要
You're really focusing on showing those findings.
你的关注点应该是你的发现
We saw this happen,
比如 我们观察到了某个数据
and it happened because of these events.
是因为这些事件的发生
Now, it's important that you still include those key recommendations.
最后 你还是需要包括你的关键建议
Again, everything is actionable.
再重复一遍 所有的建议都应该是可执行的
So have ideas on what can be done with this information.
所以 应该要对如何基于这些信息做出行动而有些自己的建议
Also, you can frame this in the context of,
当然 你也可以采取这样的结构：
why are you sharing this information?
为什么要分享这些信息？
Why are you presenting it?
为什么要做呈现？
What takeaways are going to be important there?
有什么重要的分享结果？
Now when it comes to preparing a presentation for a management,
为经理级别的人准备汇报时
things are roughly the same,
内容大致是一样的
but there's a few changes.
但是有一些不同
We also want to talk about the project's scope.
我们同样要说项目内容
These would be the tools that you use to collect the data,
但是可以包括用来收集信息的工具
the date ranges that are used to find these results,
支持你的发现的数据范围
and the volume of data that you collected.
收集到的数据量
This is because someone in management is likely going to want to make
这是因为这个级别的人可能会希望看到你是如何达到你的结论的
sure that they agree with how you arrived at this conclusion.
希望确保这个过程是合理的、正确的
Now, you'll still include your key data points,
你仍然需要讲述关键数据
because everyone's going to be interested in,
因为每个人都很关注
what are the summary of those findings?
这些发现的结论是什么？
Again, what did you measure, and why?
你是怎样衡量的？为什么？
Finally, it's okay to include note-worthy data.
最后 可以包括一些重要数据
You might exclude elements from the executive report to prevent it from being too long.
汇报给高层的时候 你可以删除一些细节 避免报告太冗长
But with management, you'll want to include that information.
汇报给经理级别 可以包括这些信息
As always, you're going to include those recommendations.
建议是永远都需要包括的
You may have thoughts and ideas,
即使对解决问题没有现成的解决方案
even if you're not sure how to solve the problem.
也需要包括你的一些想法
Now when it comes to analysts,
如果你的受众是分析师
they're going to care about everything the managers care about,
他们会希望看到所有细节
plus all of your raw data.
甚至你的初始数据
This is the time to overshare.
这时候 就要尽可能地分享所有信息
That raw data might lead to additional research projects,
基于源数据 可能会出现新的研究方向
or ways that that data can be refined.
或者重新定义数据的方法
They're going to be incredibly curious about how you arrived at these findings,
他们会对你如何达到结论非常感兴趣
and they'll want to walk through in detail,
他们会和你一起过所有的细节
the methodology on how you got there.
以及你的方法、过程
Now remember, part of action is also communicating what needs to happen.
好了 记住 行动的一部分就是传达需要改变的信息
These reports give you a valuable way to frame your thoughts,
这些报告可以让你整理你的思绪
but do so in a way that keeps it simple,
但是记住 在深度讨论的同时
while still demonstrating that you've evaluated it in depth.
要简洁明了
You want to make sure that you never assume that everyone
永远不要假设所有人都理解你的指标以及你的数据
but you also don't want to burden them with all of the details.
但同时 也不要太过注重细节
Create plenty of opportunities,
可以设置问答环节
so that the people that you're presenting to can ask
这样你的受众可以有很多机会来向你提问
questions or probe for more, if they're skeptical.
如果他们保持怀疑的话 也可以提出问题